Franz Boas Papers 1862-1942 Mss.B.B61.fourtee Mss.B.B61.inventory14
American Philosophical Society
- Franz Boas Papers - Correspondents W
  - Woodworth, R. S. -- also see Woodward, Prof. R. S. (Box 97-98)
    - To Boas, 1927 Apr. 1; 1p
    - American Negro 1p, 1929 Mar. 15; 1p
    - To Boas, 1934 Nov. 12; 1p
    - To Boas, 1934 Dec. 6; 1p
    - To National academy of Sciences Section of anthropology and psychology, 1934 Oct. 11 1933 Nov. 24; 1p 1p
    - To same, 1934 Nov. 1 1933 Nov. 24; 1p 1p
    - To Columbia Univ., 1916 Feb. 2
    - Dept. of anthropology. Graduates and friends.
  - Wooldman (Box 98)
    - To Boas, 1906 Feb. 10
  - Woolf, Joseph A. (Box 98)
    - From Boas, 1934 May 11; 1p
    - From Boas, 1934 Aug. 25; 1p
    - To Boas, 1934 May 1; 1p
    - To Boas, 1934 Aug. 16; 1p
  - Woollen, C. T. (Box 98)
    - From Boas, 1929 July 23; 1p
  - Woolley, H. T. (Box 98)
    - To Boas, 1926 Nov. 13; 1p
  - Woolley, Mary E. (Box 98)
    - From Boas, 1914 Sep. 24
    - See Boas, F. (to Shipler, G. E.), 1941 Sep. 17
    - To Boas, 1914 Sep. 3
    - To Boas, 1914 Sep. 28
    - To Boas, 1936 Aug. 13; 1p
    - See Boas, F. open letter on culture and democracy in Spain. Replies., 1938 Jan.
      See Baker, Frank E. (open letter)
    - Found at end of Dec. 1939
    - To Boas, 1941 Aug. 1; 1p
    - From Knox, O. A., 1940 Aug. 6
    - Attached to Woolley, M. E., 1940 Aug. 1
    - From Knox, O. A., 1940 Dec. 7
    - From Knox, O. A., 1941 Nov. 7; 1p
  - Worchester National Bank (Box 98)
    - To Boas, 1899 Mar. 6; 1p
  - Wordie, J. M. (Box 98)
    - From Boas, 1939 Mar. 27; 1p
    - To Boas, 1939 Mar. 6; 1p
  - Work, Lincoln T. (Box 98)
    - From Boas, 1927 Mar. 9; 1p
    - To Boas, 1927 Mar. 7; 1p
      Enc: Announcement of meeting and list of candidates of Kappa chapter of Sigma Xi.
  - Work, Monroe N. (Box 98)
    - From Boas, 1920 July 13; 1p
    - To Boas, 1920 June 14; 1p
  - Workingman's School (Ward, D.J.H.) (Box 98)
    - To Boas, 1888 Oct. 23
    - To Boas, 1889 Mar. 12
    - To Boas, 1889 Mar. 12
    - To Boas, 1890 Apr. 19
    - To Boas, 1891 Oct. 14
    - To Boas, 1891 Oct. 24
  - World Congress of Jewish Physicians (Box 98)
    - Found at end of Aug. 1936, 2p
  - World Peaceways (Box 98)
    - First quarterly report for 1933. See Durlach, T. M., 1933 Mar. 31
      - Report, 1933 Apr. 31; 3p
  - World Power Conference (Box 98)
    See Merrill, O. C.
  - World Telegram. Editor (Box 98)
    - From Boas, 1938 May 5; 1p
    - See McAney, B. O., 1935 Jan. 22; 1p
    - From Boas, 1935 Feb. 25; 1p
    - From Garcia Diaz, A., 1937 Oct. 10
    - Enc. with Garcia Diaz, A., 1937 Oct. 12
    - See Boas, F. (to NY Post-Editor), 1941 Nov. 27
  - World's Columbian Commission (Box 98)
    - To Boas, 1894 May 16
  - World's Work - Editor (Box 98)
    - To Boas, 1909 Apr. 14
  - Worman, J. H. (Box 98)
    - To Keppel, F. P., 1906 June 13
  - Wornom, Herman E. (Box 98)
    - From Boas, 1935 Mar. 18; 1p
  - Wortendyke, Rynier Esq. (Box 98)
    - From Boas, 1910 July 27
    - To Boas, 1910 July 27
  - Wovner, Wilhelm (Box 98)
    - To Boas, 1920 Nov. 3; 3p
  - Wreszinski, Walter (Box 98)
    - From Boas, 1923 Mar. 5; 1p
  - Wright (Box 98)
    - To Boas, 1898 Dec. 5
  - Wright, Corinne (Box 98)
    - To Boas, 1934 Feb. 2; 1p
  - Wright, E. H. (Box 98)
    - From Boas, 1931 Mar. 16; 1p
  - Wright, H. C. (Box 98)
    - From Laufer, B., 1905 Apr. 11
  - Wright, J. H. Archaeological Institute (Box 98)
    - To Putnam, F. W., 1898 Dec. 5; 1p
  - Wright, John S. (Box 98)
    - To Boas, 1909 Oct. 12
  - Wright, R. R. (Box 98)
    - To Boas, 1906 Oct. 24
    - To Boas, 1906 Dec. 1
    - To Boas, 1907 Jan. 2
    - To Boas, 1913 July 2
    - From Boas, 1907 Feb. 27; 1p
  - Wülfing, John Max (Box 98)
    - From Boas, 1920 Feb. 16; 3p
    - From Boas, 1920 Feb. 21; 4p
    - From Boas, 1920 Feb. 24; 2p
    - From Boas, 1920 Mar. 1; 2p
    - From Boas, 1920 Mar. 10; 2p
    - From Boas, 1920 July 19; 2p
    - From Boas, 1920 July 20; 1p
    - From Boas, 1920 July 31; 1p
    - From Boas, 1920 Aug. 17; 1p
    - From Boas, 1920 Sep. 10; 2p
    - From Boas, 1922 Oct. 12; 1p
    - From Boas, 1928 May 22; 1p
    - From Boas, 1928 May 29; 1p
    - From Boas, 1928 Nov. 28; 1p
    - To Boas, 1920 Feb. 17; 1p
    - To Boas, 1920 Feb. 19; 1p
    - To Boas, 1920 July 28; 1p
    - Enc: list of the subscribers to St. Louis Fund for the German Universities., 1920 Aug. 11; 1p
    - To Boas, 1928 May 24; 1p
    - Found at end of 1928, 1p
    - To G. E. Stechert & Co., 1922 Aug. 22; 2p
    - To Same, 1922 Sep. 2; 1p
  - Wunderlich, F. (Box 98)
    - From Boas, 1936 Apr. 13; 2p
  - Wundt, W. (Box 98)
    - To Boas, 1883 Feb. 22
  - Wuoranen, J. (Box 98)
    - From Boas, 1934 Dec. 14; 1p
  - Wurlitzer, Howard E. (Box 98)
    - From Boas, 1920 Mar. 5; 3p
    - From Boas, 1920 July 20; 1p
    - From Boas, 1920 July 30; 1p
    - From Boas, 1920 July 31; 1p
    - From Boas, 1920 Aug. 9; 1p
    - From Boas, 1920 Aug. 16; 1p
    - From Boas, 1920 Nov. 15; 1p
    - To Boas, 1920 Mar. 2; 1p
      - Letter: 6/7/20 Enc., 1920 July 26; 2p-1
        General note
        1
      - Letter: 7/24/20 Enc., 1920 July 27; 1p-2
      - Emergency Society in Aid of European Science & Art, 1920 Aug. 12; 1p
        2
    - From Gundlach, Ernest, 1920 June 7; 2p
    - To Gundlach, Ernest T., 1920 July 24; 1p
  - Würtembergische Verein (Box 98)
    - To Boas, 1932 Apr. 7; 1p
  - Wurzinger, D. (Box 98)
    - To Boas, 1933 May 20; 2p
    - To Hrdlicka, A., 1933 June 1; 2p
  - Würzburg: Chemisches Institut der Universitat (Box 98)
    - To Boas, 1923 Feb. 10
  - Wyer, S. S. (Box 98)
    - From Boas, 1941 Dec. 4; 1p
  - Wyhl, H. (Box 98)
    - To Boas, 1918 May 26; 2p
  - Wyman, H. Winfield (Box 98)
    - To Waites, Alfred, 1892 Jan. 3; 2p
    - From Boas, 1892 Jan. 8; 2p
  - Wyman, Loraine (Miss) (Box 98)
    - From Boas, 1919 May 14; 1p
    - From Boas, 1921 Apr. 18; 1p
    - To Boas, 1921 Apr. 19; 1p
  - Wyman, W. C. (Box 98)
    - To Boas, 1893 Dec. 23; 1p
  - Wynne, Clara (Box 98)
    - From Boas, 1933 Nov. 10; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 Nov. 7; 1p
- Franz Boas Papers - Correspondents Y
  - Yacoubian, Adour H. (Box 98)
    - To Boas, 1936 May 11; 1p
  - Yager, Arthur (Box 98)
    - To Britton, N. L., 1916 Aug. 16; 2p
    - From Britton, N. L., 1917 Jan. 28
    - From Britton, N. L., 1917 June 28
  - Yale University Graduate School Dean (Box 98)
    - From Boas, 1921 Mar. 7; 1p
  - Yale University Press (Box 98)
    - From Boas, 1914 Dec. 21
    - To Boas, 1920 Apr. 24; 1p
      See Donaldson, Norman
  - Yale University Summer School (Box 98)
    - From Boas, 1906 Aug. 16
  - Yamamoto, M. T. (Box 98)
    - From Boas, 1915 Nov. 24
  - Yampolsky, R. N. (Box 98)
    - To Boas, 1925 Dec. 30; 1p
    - Found at end of Dec. 1933
  - Yanes, Francisco J. (Box 98)
    - From Boas, 1914 Dec. 5
    - To Boas, 1908 Aug. 7; 8p
    - To Boas, 1915 Jan. 14
  - Yarmolinsky, Abraham (Box 98)
    - To Boas, 1913 Aug. 7
  - Yarnall, Stanley R. (Box 98)
    - From Boas, 1917 Mar. 12
    - From Boas, 1917 Mar. 15
    - From Boas, 1917 Mar. 16; 2p
    - From Boas, 1917 Mar. 16
    - From Boas, 1917 Mar. 21
    - From Boas, 1917 Mar. 31
    - From Boas, 1917 Apr. 2
    - From Boas, 1917 Apr. 3
    - From Boas, 1917 Apr. 11; 3p
    - From Boas, 1917 Apr. 17; 2p
    - From Boas, 1917 May 9
    - From Boas, 1917 May 14
    - From Boas, 1917 May 19
    - From Boas, 1917 May 23
    - To Boas, 1917 Mar. 16
    - To Boas, 1917 Mar. 20
    - To Boas, 1917 Apr. 4
    - To Boas, 1917 Apr. 16
    - To Boas, 1917 Apr. 25
    - To Boas, 1917 May 17
    - To Boas, 1917 May 21
    - To Boas, 1920 Apr. 13; 1p
  - Yate, H. W. (Box 98)
    - To Boas, 1911 Oct. 5
    - To Boas, 1912 Mar. 26
    - To Boas, 1913 Apr. 23; 2p
    - To Boas, 1913 June 4
  - Yates, Haydie (Box 98)
    - To Boas, 1936 Apr. 2
    - To Boas, 1936 May 29; 1p
  - Yatschet, Louise (Box 98)
    - To Boas, 1913 July 7
  - Yeatts, M.W.W.M. (Box 98)
    - To Janardhana, R., 1932 June 2; 1p
  - Yeggle, B. S. (Mrs. Bessie S.) (Box 98)
    - To Boas, 1913 Dec. 19
    - From Boas, 1913 Dec. 23
  - Yenser, Thomas (Box 98)
    - To Meinhof, K., 1926 Apr. 13; 1p
  - Yergan, Max (Box 98)
    - From Boas, 1939 Dec. 9; 1p
    - From Boas, 1941 May 12; 1p
    - From Boas, 1941 Dec. 4; 1p
    - From Boas, 1941 Dec. 5; 1p
    - From Boas, 1942 Feb. 19; 1p
    - To Boas, 1939 Nov. 30; 2p
    - To Boas, 1939 Dec. 8; 1p
    - To Boas, 1941 May 7; 1p
    - To Boas, 1941 Dec. 11; 2p
    - Enc: Outline and list, 1941 Dec. 16; 1p
    - To Boas, 1942 Feb. 18; 1p
  - Yerkes, Dr. Robert M. (Box 98)
    - To Boas, 1923 June 15; 2p
    - To Boas, 1927 Mar. 30; 1p
    - From Boas, 1927 Mar. 22; 1p
    - See Boas, F. (to Woodworth, R.S.), 1931 Sep. 2
  - Ygnacio Otero (Box 98)
    - To Boas, 1912 Mar. 30
  - Yiddish scientific institute (Box 98)
    - See enclosure with Sapir, E., 1933 Mar. 29
  - Yngvantielsey (Box 98)
    - To Boas, 1910 Oct. 22
  - Yoffie, Miss Leah (Box 98)
    - From Boas, 1920 Mar. 4; 2p
    - From Boas, 1920 Mar. 31; 1p
    - From Boas, 1920 Oct. 3; 1p
    - To Boas, 1920 Feb. 23; 1p
    - To Boas, 1920 Mar. 29; 2p
    - To Boas, 1920 Apr. 13; 2p
  - Yohanssan (Box 98)
    - To Boas, 1906 Mar. 21
  - Yolles, P.P. (Box 98)
    - To Boas, 1933 Jan. 4; 3p
  - Yost, Charles W. (Box 98)
    - To Boas, 1939 Feb. 2; 2p
  - Youmans, E. L. Popular Science Monthly (Box 98)
    - To Boas, 1885 Feb. 3; 2p
  - Youmans, W. J. Popular Science Monthly (Box 98)
    - To Boas, 1885 Feb. 24; 2p
    - To Boas, 1894 June 19
    - To Boas, 1894 July 20
    - To Boas, 1894 July 25
    - To Boas, 1897 Feb. 17; 1p
  - Young, Allyn A. (Box 98)
    - From Boas, 1917 Dec. 3
    - From Bielaski, A. B., 1917 Dec. 4
    - From Cattell, J. M., 1917 Nov. 11; 9p
    - To Seligman, E. R., 1926 Mar. 8; 1p
    - Enc. with Seligman, E. R., 1926 Mar. 31
    - From Walcott, C. D., 1917 Nov. 24
    - To Walcott, C. D., 1917 Nov. 23
  - Young, Ching-chi (Box 98)
    - From Boas, 1933 Mar. 21; 1p
    - To Boas, 1932 Oct. 22; 2p
  - Young, Donald (Box 98)
    - From Boas, 1933 Dec. 29; 1p
    - From Boas, 1935 Jan. 3; 1p
    - From Boas, 1936 June 2; 1p
    - From Boas, 1937 Feb. 11; 1p
    - From Boas, 1937 June 24; 1p
    - From Boas, 1937 Dec. 2; 1p
    - From Boas, 1938 Nov. 9; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 May 9; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 Dec. 8; 1p
    - To Boas, 1935 Jan. 4; 1p
    - To Boas, 1937 June 30; 1p
    - To Boas, 1937 Dec. 6; 1p
    - To Boas, 1938 Jan. 10; 1p
    - To Boas, 1938 Feb. 28; 2p
    - To Boas, 1938 May 23; 1p
    - To Boas, 1938 Sep. 19; 1p
    - To Boas, 1938 Oct. 20; 1p
    - Enc: (Boas, F.) Studies of modern population., 1938 Oct. 27; 1p
    - Found at end of July 1939
      See Boas, F. Paper on modern population.
  - Young, F. D. (Box 98)
    - To Boas, 1931 June 19; 2p
  - Young, J. Lowe (Box 98)
    - To Gies, W. J., 1918 Apr. 4; 2p
  - Young, L. Walton (Box 98)
    - From Boas, 1930 May 3; 1p
    - To Boas, 1930 Apr. 24; 1p
  - Young, Mrs. Pauline (Box 98)
    - From Boas, 1930 June 2; 1p
    - To Boas, 1930 June 7; 1p
  - Young, Stark (Box 98)
    - From Boas, 1920 Apr. 9; 1p
  - Young Men's Hebrew Association (Box 98)
    See Rosenthal, Abraham
- Franz Boas Papers - Correspondents Z
  - Zabriskie, C. B. (Box 98)
    - To Boas, 1906 Jan. 8; 1p
  - Zabriskie, J. (Box 98)
    - From Boas, 1908 Dec. 21
  - Zach, E. (Box 98)
    - From Boas, 1925 Apr. 29; 1p
    - To Boas, 1925 Mar. 23; 3p
  - Zahn, Alfred (Box 98)
    - See Boas, F. (open letter), 1942 Jan. 29
  - Zeitlin, B. (Box 98)
    - To Boas, 1938 May 21; 1p
  - Zentgraf, Amy (Box 98)
    - To Boas, 1898 Mar. 4; 2p
  - Zhitlowsky, Chaim (Box 98)
    - Found at end of Dec. 1941, 1p
    - 1941 Nov. 11
  - Ziegler (Box 98)
    - To Boas, 1920 Oct. 23; 1p
  - Ziegler, K. (Box 98)
    - To Boas, 1910 Feb. 11; 1p
    - To Boas, 1910 Apr. 19; 1p
  - Zigmond, Maurice L. (Box 98)
    - Found at end of Dec. 1937, 1p
  - Zimm, Bruno Louis (Box 98)
    - From Boas, 1905 May 23
    - To Boas, 1905 May 19
  - Zimmerman, William (Box 98)
    - To Boas, 1935 June 4; 1p
  - Zinger, A. (Box 98)
    - To Boas, 1908 Nov. 10; 1p
    - To Boas, 1909 Feb. 24; 1p
    - To Boas, 1909 Apr. 20; 2p
    - To Boas, 1923 Apr. 14; 2p
    - To Boas, 1933 Mar. 6; 2p
    - To Boas, 1933 Mar. 19; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 Mar. 31; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 Apr. 24; 2p
    - To Boas, 1933 Apr. 24; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 Apr. 14; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 July 10; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 July 15; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 July 18; 1p
    - To Boas, 1934 Jan. 9; 1p
    - To Boas, 1934 Feb 2, Feb. 24; 1p
    - To Boas, 1934 Sep. 21; 2p
    - To Boas, 1935 Feb. 3; 1p
    - To Boas, 1935 June 10; 1p
    - To Boas, 1935 June 22; 1p
    - To Boas, 1935 Aug. 2; 1p
    - To Boas, 1935 Aug. 4
    - To Boas, 1935 Sep. 25; 2p
    - To Boas, 1935 Nov. 15; 1p
  - Zinken, Miss Ann (Box 98)
    - From Boas, 1933 Jan. 27; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 Jan. 26; 1p
  - Zinser, Rudolf (Box 98)
    - To Boas, 1889 Feb. 22
  - Zinsser, August (Box 98)
    - To Boas, 1904 Nov. 7; 1p
    - To Boas, 1905 Jan. 21; 1p
    - To Boas, 1905 Jan. 24; 1p
    - Found at end of 1905, 1p
  - Zinsser, H. (Box 98)
    - From Boas, 1921 Mar. 17; 1p
  - Zintgraff, E., 1895 July 8; 1p (Box 98)
  - Zipf, George K. (Box 98)
    - From Boas, 1937 June 17; 1p
    - From Boas, 1938 May 23; 2p
    - To Boas, 1937 June 15; 1p
    - To Boas, 1938 May 21; 1p
    - To Boas, 1938 May 31; 1p
  - Zoellner, Clara (Box 98)
    - From Boas, 1910 Apr. 28; 1p
    - From Boas, 1910 Apr. 30; 1p
    - To Boas, 1910 Apr. 26; 4p
    - Found at end of 1910, 2p
  - Zoller, Charles (Box 98)
    - From Boas, 1923 Feb. 2; 1p
    - Enc: letter from Schelle, Reinhold to Boas, F., 1923 Jan. 9
  - Zollschan, I. -- (sometimes J.) (Box 98)
    - From Boas, 1926 Jan. 7; 1p
    - From Boas, 1926 Feb. 17; 1p
    - From Boas, 1926 Feb. 26; 1p
    - From Boas, 1927 Feb. 11; 1p
    - From Boas, 1934 Jan. 29; 1p
    - From Boas, 1938 Dec. 6; 2p
    - To Boas, 1925 Feb. 11; 1p
    - To Boas, 1926 Dec. 22; 2p
    - To Boas, 1933 Dec. 31; 4p
    - To Boas, 1934 Apr. 8; 2p
    - Enc: Zollschan, J. (to Ruppin), 1934 Apr. 7
    - To Boas, 1934 Apr. 24
    - Enc. with Schneiderman, H., 1934 June 14; 8p
    - To Boas, 1934 Oct. 1; 10p
    - To Boas, 1934 Oct. 1; 14p
    - Found at end of Dec. 1934, 7p
    - To Boas, 1935 Jan. 29; 1p
    - To Boas, 1936 Jan. 4; 4p
    - To Ruppin, 1934 Apr. 7; 3p
    - Enc. with Zollschan, J., 1934 Apr. 8
    - To Warburg, M., 1933 Dec. 30; 3p
    - Enc. with Schneiderman, H., 1934 Feb. 13
    - To Warburg, F. M., 1933 Dec.; 1p
    - Enc. with Schneiderman, H., 1934 Feb. 13
  - Zoologisch-Botanische Gesellschaft in Wien (Box 98)
    - To Boas, 1926 Apr. 14; 1p
      See Also
    - Boas, F. (to Handlirsch, A.), 1926 May 6
  - Zrisen (Box 98)
    - To Boas, 1903 Dec.
  - Zuehlsdorff, Volkmar (Box 98)
    - From Boas, 1940 Apr. 2; 1p
    - To Boas, 1940 Mar. 27; 1p
    - To Boas, 1940 Feb. 5; 1p
  - Zukunft, Editor (Box 98)
    - From Boas, 1938 Dec. 12; 1p
    - To Boas, 1938 Nov. 29; 1p
  - Zwirner, Eberhard (Box 98)
    - From Boas, 1932 Feb. 13; 1p
    - From Boas, 1932 May 11; 1p
    - From Boas, 1933 Feb. 21
    - From Boas, 1933 Apr. 24; 1p
    - From Boas, 1933 July 25; 1p
    - From Boas, 1933 Aug. 21; 1p
    - From Boas, 1936 June 23; 1p
    - To Boas, 1932 Apr. 29; 1p
    - To Boas, 1932 Nov. 5; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 Jan. 10; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 Apr. 6; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 July 28
    - To Boas, 1933 Sep. 4; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 Nov. 25; 1p
    - To Boas, 1936 June 12; 1p
    - To Boas, 1936 July 26; 4p
    - To Boas, 1936 Sep. 7; 1p